PON.ARIVANANTHAM



1/482A, Murugesan Nagar,

Thoraipakkam, Chennai – 600 097.

Email: arivanantham.1972@gmail.com

Phone: 9444290474

Career Objective

A highly talented, skilled and dynamic educational leader with 24 years of experience in creating effective learning environment and a proven track record in increasing student's academic skills, is looking for a Principal or Dean or Director position in your reputed College.

EDUCATION

• Ph.D. in Computer Science, Sathyabama University, Chennai.

Emphasis: Pattern Matching and Network Security

• ME in Computer Science, Sathyabama University, Chennai.

Emphasis: Data Compression

• BE in Computer Science, A.K. College of Engineering, Krishnan Kovil, Srivilliputhur Madurai Kamaraj University, Madurai.

EXPERIENCE

SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE

Experience in Administration : 17.10 Years

Experience in Teaching : 6.6 Years

Organisation	Position	Form	То	Duration in Yrs
Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan college of Engg & Tech	Vice Principal	06.06.2008	28.12.2018	10.6
Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan college of Engg & Tech	Head of the Department	06.06.2006	05.06.2008	2
Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan college of Engg & Tech	Lecturer	26.12.2003	06.06.2004	0.6

C.P.A. College of Arts	Lecturer	01.06.1993	06.06.1999	6
Netsource Computers	Programmer	15.06.1999	05.12.2001	1.6
Enviro Soft Pvt Ltd	Project Leader	04.01.2002	10.09.2003	1.8

ADMINISTRATIVE AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Title: Vice Principal

06.06.2008 to 28.12.2018

- Handled entire College activities in the absence of the principal
- Assisting principal in evaluating teachers performance and College activities
- Reviewing and building positive learning environment for students
- Prepared College Academic calendar and handled purchase of books for the College
- Meeting parents and discussing their concern over safety and education quality
- Inspected safety and security measures and ensure no relapse

Title: NAAC, NBA Coordinator

06.06.2008 to till date

Heading of IQAC committee, worked for 2 NAAC Committees and 3 NBA Committees

Title: AICTE, Anna University Inspection Coordinator

26.12.2003 to till date

Preparing documents, submitting applications and supervising the inspection process

Title: Exam Cell Coordinator

06.06.2009 to till date

12 times served as a Chief Superintendent, 6 times as a AUR and also involving paper valuation and other exam related activities.

Title: Head of the Department

06.06.2006 to 05.06.2008

- Organizing and supervising extracurricular activities in the College
- Resolved staffing issues by speaking them individually and recommended promotion of deserving candidate
- Meeting parents and discussing their concern over education quality

- Prepared Academic calendar
- Reviewing and building positive learning environment for students

Title: Heads of various Committees

06.06.2006 to till date

Member in Governing council for 3 years, 10 years of heading in discipline committee, 12 years of heading in Hostel co-ordination committee, 5 years of maintaining Transport department and 10 years heading in Academic audit committee and member in various committees in the working period.

Title: Project Leader

04.01 2002 to 10.09.2003

- Responsible for handling the project from the front.
- Effectively make the plan of the particular project.
- Presenting the plan in front of seniors and take suggestions from them.
- Giving a presentation to the Junior Staff and make them understand the important aspects of the project.
- Ensuring that all the resources are available for the project.
- Delegating work and supervising the activities of junior IT staff.
- Recommending and implementing technological improvements and efficiencies

Tilte: Programmer

15.06.1999 to 05.12, 2001

Created Many Projects and documentation, using C++ and Visual Basic, to manage various projects. Wrote design document, test plan, and user documentation. Enhanced C library functions, for reliable shared access to the mount table. Developed a new libc function & fixed defects in other functions

TEACHING EXPERIENCE:

Title: Lecturer

01.06.1993 to 06.07.1999 and 26.12.2003 to 07.06.2004

- Taught computer programs, algorithms, and computer languages to students
- Created and assigned projects to students and developed professional skills in them
- Utilized college and public library and collected teaching materials
- Worked with students struggling in understanding concepts of computer programming

- Informing staff of key priorities, providing assistance, and evaluating their work
- Taught courses and assigned passing students actual IT projects

PROJECT MANAGEMENT AND SUPERVISION

During this experience, guided 20+ projects in the UG and PG Level students and completing 4 large projects in Software Company.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSIP

- Member in Computer Society of India
- Member in IEEE

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. M.Imayavaramban, Pon.Arivanantham, "Energy Management System and Theft Detection", *International Journal of Applied Engineering Research*, Volume 10, Number 8 (2015) pp. 20895-20902.
- 2. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Parallel Communicating Flip Pushdown Automata Systems Communicating by Stacks", *European Journal of Scientific Research*, Vol.81 No.2 (2012), pp.270-284.
- 3. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Memory Efficiency of Multiple Pattern Matching for Network Security using Extend Finite State Machine", *European Journal of Scientific Research*, Vol. 86 No 4 September, 2012, pp.553-555.
- 4. PON.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "A Memory-Efficient In Scalable String Pattern Matching Method For Integrated Deterministic Finite Deep Packet Inspection", *International Journal of Applied Engineering Research*, Volume 10, Number 6 (2015) pp. 15545-15559.
- 5. M.Imayavaramban, PON.Arivanantham, "Energy Management System for Home Appliance with Theft Control System", *International Journal of Digital Communication and Networks*, Volume 2, Issue 2, February 2015, pp. 12 15.
- 6. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Auxiliary Information in Data Privacy and Attacks for Secure Multiparty Protocols", *International Journal for Modern Trends in Science and Technology*, Volume: 03, Issue No: 02, February 2017, pp. 48 51.
- 7. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Reduce the False Positive and False Negative from Real Traffic with Intrusion Detection", *International Journal Of Engineering And Science*, Vol.05, Issue 01 (January 2015), PP: 09-14.

- 8. M.Mukilarasi, Pon.Arivanantham, "Selection of an Optimal Transmission path using VADD", *International Journal of Computer Science and Management Research*, Vol 1 Issue 3 October 2012, pp. 445 448.
- 9. R. Aruna Devi, Pon.Arivanantham, "Interfirewall Optimization across Administrative Domains for Enabling Privacy Preserving and Security", *International Journal of Computer Science and Information Technologies*, Vol. 4 (6), 2013, pp. 808-812.
- 10. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Statistical Quality of Service to Increase Qos/Qoe of IP-Based Gateway for Integrating Heterogeneous Wireless Devices", *International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications, Vol. 7, No. 1, 2016, pp.325 336.*
- 11. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "A LOW COST DFA BASED DEEP PACKET INSPECTION OF COMPRESSED WEB TRAFFIC", *International Conference on Big Data Analytical and Internet of Things (IoT)* SRM University, 23rd March 2016.
- 12. Pon.Arivanantham, Dr. M.Ramakrishnan, "Data Forwarding Using Two Way Communications in Vehicular Ad-Hoc Network", *National Conference on Emerging Trends in Computer Applications and Management*, VINAYAKA MISSIONS UNIVERSITY, 24th 25th February, 2012
- 13. A.Dhanalakshmi, Pon.Arivanantham, "Synchronization Algorithm For Mobile Database Based On Message Digest", *Proceedings of International Conference on Futuristic Trends in Computer Science Engineering & Information Technology ICCT2011*, Thiruvalluvar College of Engineering and Technology,
- **14.** Minnu Mathew, Pon.Arivanantham, "OPTIMAL USER-CENTRIC ALLOCATION FOR ROGRESSIVE PACKET ARRIVALS IN PTNS", *1st International Conference on Research Vogues in information & Communication Technologies*. DMI Engineering College, Aralvailllozhi. vol. 1.No. 1. Febraury -2014
- 15. R.Vidhyalakshmi, Pon.Arivanantham, "Attack Identification in Peer to Peer Network based on Chaotic Analysis", *International Journal of Engineering Research & Technology (IJERT) TITCON-2015 Conference Proceedings*, AVS Engineering College, 8 & 9 April 2015, pp. 110 112.

PERSONAL DETAILS

D.OB : 11.04.1972

Fathers Name : S.PONRAM (Retd H.M.)

Mothers Name : S.LAKSHMI (Retd H.M.)

Address : 1/482A, Murugesan Nagar, Thoraipakkam, Chennai – 97

Email: <u>arivanantham.1972@gmail.co</u>m

REFERENCES

1. Dr.R.Ponraj,

Former Principal, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Institute of Technology, Samayapuram, Trichy.

2. Dr. M.Ramakrsihnan

Professor and Head, Department of Information and Technology,

Madurai Kamaraj University, Madurai

3. Dr. S.Gowri,

Director, EMMRC, Anna University, Chennai.

4. Thiru P.Neelaraj

Secretary, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan College of Engineering, Coimbatore

5. Dr. M.Dharmendra Kumar

Former Additional Controller of Examination, Associate Professor, Department of Chemical Technology, AC Tech., Chennai

Signature